# MD Najrul Islam Sumon

#### REACT DEVELOPER

45/1, Hazipara, Rampura, Dhaka - 1217, Rep. of BANGLADESH

© (+880) 1845393505 | M nazrul2517@gmail.com | ⊕najrulislam | ♠najrul04 | in najrul04

#### SUMMARY

I'm an experienced React developer with a strong foundation in JavaScript, ReactJS, Redux, NextJS, and TailwindCSS. I possess excellent adaptability and can work efficiently in both team and independent work environment, with a strong drive to continuously learn and master emerging technologies.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS\_

**Expertise:** HTML5, CSS3, Tailwind CSS, Bootstrap5, JavaScript, ES6, React JS, GitHub, React Router **Fundamentals:** TypeScript, Node JS, Express JS, NoSQL, Firebase, MongoDB, Next JS, Redux, RestAPI, Wordpress, PHP, jQuery, Figma

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### FRONT END DEVELOPER, INVENT

#### JAN 2023 – PRESENT

- Design and develop React web app from the scratch to give the company an online existence for potential customers to reach.
- Implement Firebase authentication system with 10,000 authentication request such as email/password, Phone authentication, Third-party authentication per day for free and 100,000 per month for free.
- Create with a library of JavaScript named React JS because of its potential to reuse components which makes the code and website easy to maintain.
- Ensure easy and fast coding with maximum customization options by using Tailwind CSS and raw CSS to develop a responsive website to kept the code clean and easily manageable.
- By utilizing React Router, a private routing system was implemented to ensure ease of editing, reliability and maintainability.
- Implement Node JS and its framework Express JS for the backend technology, data storage is achieved for using MongoDB.

## FRONT END DEVELOPER, VECTOR DESIGN US, INC.

JAN 2022 – DEC 2022

- Responsible for developing a custom website that supported more than 20,000 users. Utilizing modern UI Stack such as: Wordpress PHP, Raw CSS and jQuery.
- Prepared website update proposals to presents to manager, provide technical support to clients and writing code using HTML and CSS.
- Managed a user guide to help and understand site features and management of the websites.
- · Updated website as instructed by the company and introduce new features and contents
- Managed comments from visitors, including private emails and comments posted on the site.
- Introduced new plug-ins and extensions to make the website more usable and interactive in order to have better user experience.

# **EDUCATION**

## **BIST (Bangladesh Institute of Science and Technology)**

## **National University of Bangladesh**

Bachelor in Business Administration (Marketing)

JUN. 2016 - DEC. 2020

#### **Programming Hero**

Complete Web Development Certificate 2021 in 24 weeks

JUN. 2021 - NOV. 2021

## freeCodeCamp

Responsive Web Design JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures JUN. 2021 MAR. 2023

## LANGUAGE\_